# 所有的外边卖的网红菜脆皮虾
Crispy Shrimp, a popular dish sold by restaurants everywhere
# 魏刚强把这配方无私的
Wei Gangqiang shares this recipe selflessly
# 通过老饭骨奉献出来了
Dedicate this recipe through Lao Fan Gu
# 扬头
Raising head
# 翘尾
Raising tails
# 蜜汁酥皮虾
Honey-glazed crispy shrimp
# 应广大网友的要求
A lot of friends asked us
# 咱解密一下
To reveal (how this dish is made)
# 介绍一下主配料
Let's introduce the main ingredients
# 主料是白虾
The main ingredient is white shrimps
# 处理了啊 处理的
Have been cleaned and deveined? Yes, cleaned and deveined.
# 蜂蜜 20克
Honey 20g
# 苹果醋 45克
Apple cider vinegar, 45g
# 米醋 75克
Rice vinegar, 75g
# 白醋 15克
White vinegar, 15g
# 冰糖 50克
White rock sugar, 50g
# 白糖 50克
White sugar, 50g
# 桂花 糖桂花 20克
Osmanthus, osmanthus syrup, 20g
# 这些料能做3份酥皮虾
You can make 3 portions of crispy shrimp with those ingredients
# 别侃了赶紧做菜吧
No more chatting, hurry up making the dish!
# 第一步虾腿
First step, pereiopods and pleopods (legs)
# 虾腿给它去了
Get rid of them all
# 虾腔剪了
Cut off its rostrum (pointing part on the head)
# 背开
Open its abdomen (back)
# 背开完了以后
After open its back,
# 虾线去掉
Remove the vein
# 去完了以后斩两刀
After that, cut with the tip of the knife in the middle
# 斩断了
Chopped
# 这点我们网友要注意
This is a key point worth noticing
# 这虾腰那有根筋
There is a tendon along the abdomen
# 这筋你要斩不断的话它会弯腰
If you didn’t chop the tendon, shrimps will curl up
# 咱给它冲了
Rinse it
# 这虾脑就不要了
We don’t need the head
# 处理干净了
Clean it up
# 冲完了出来以后漂亮 效果好
It looks prettier after rinsing
# 搁在盆里头再给它腌一下
Leave them in a bowl and marinade them.
# 葱姜
Green onion, ginger
# 葱段 姜片
Big chunks of green onion and ginger slices
# 给它腌一下
Let’s marinade it.
# 黄酒
Huangjiu rice wine
# 少加点胡椒粉
Some white pepper
# 加点盐
Some salt
# 搁点盐搁点酒 葱姜 胡椒粉
Add some salt, rice wine, green onion, ginger, white pepper
# 先腌着 第二步咱把这汁给它熬了
Leave them to marinade. Step two, let’s make sauce
# 苹果醋
Apple cider vinegar
# 米醋
Rice vinegar
# 白醋
White vinegar
# 冰糖
White rock sugar
# 白糖
White sugar
# 中小火啊
Medium low heat
# 咱给它熬化了
Let’s boil it until the sugar is dissolved
# 来 加点盐
Here, add some salt
# 这汁熬好了以后
After the sauce is done
# 搁四五天没问题
You can keep it for four or five days
# 所有外边卖的网红菜脆皮虾
All the crispy shrimp they sold outside
# 魏刚强把这配方
Wei Gangqiang now shares the recipe selflessly
# 无私的通过老饭骨奉献出来了
Dedicate this recipe through Lao Fan Gu
# 化开了 关火
It’s dissolved. Turn off the heat
# 20克糖桂花加进去
Add 20 grams of osmanthus syrup
# 最后加蜂蜜
Add honey at the end
# 可以炸虾了
Now we can fry the shrimp
# 普通的色拉油
Cooking oil
# 来点淀粉
Add some starch
# 干淀粉
Dry starch
# 这虾蘸的时候
When you dip the shrimp
# 光蘸这虾肉
Only dip shrimp meat with starch
# 皮千万不能蘸
Keep the shell clean
# 皮蘸了以后它就不漂亮了
If it touch the starch, the shell will not look pretty
# 这酥皮虾要好吃的话
To make this dish tasty,
# 就是虾刚蜕完皮
You need to choose those shrimps just molted
# 那皮薄一炸就酥
The shell is thin so it will be super crispy after deep-frying
# 而且这个虾皮啊
Besides, the shell
# 它有大量的钙
Contains a lot of Calcuim
# 像那个70年代啊
Back in the 70’s,
# 家里要弄俩虾
If you could have some shrimps at home,
# 虾皮不能扔了
You wouldn’t throw away the shell.
# 单独炸一个虾米皮
Use the shell to make “Xia Mi Pi” (deep-fried shrimp shell)
# 倍酥倍脆
Extremely crispy
# 弄点二锅头喝酒
(Eat it) with some Er Guo tou (cheap spirit)
# 撒点椒盐 一点不浪费
Sprinkle some pepper salt and eat them all.
# 排好队 可以炸虾了
Order it up, now we can fry shrimps.
# 油温必须得够啊炸这虾
We should fry the shrimps at high enough temperature
# 得六成到七成
About 60-70% (180C – 210C)
# 漂亮
Beautiful
# 捞出来
Take it out
# 你看这虾啊
You see this shrimp
# 红红的 这皮一看就脆
Red colored, this shell looks crispy
# 还得复炸一遍
Need to fry it again
# 好 再来一遍
Ok, one more time.
# 捞出来
Take it out.
# 你听这皮
Listen, the shell
# 特别脆啊
Very crispy
# 把油倒出去
Pour the oil out
# 再给它刷一下
Let’s rinse it.
# 好了
Ok.
# 擦一下
Dry it.
# 少搁油 溜一下
Add a little bit of oil, spread and coat the wok.
# 下干辣椒 煸出香味来
Add dry chili and stir fry until the aroma releases
# 葱 姜 蒜
Green onion, ginger, garlic.
# 葱姜蒜小料
# 火不要太大了
The heat doesn’t need to be too high
# 把这汁 浇进去
Pour the sauce in
# 大火
Switch to high heat
# 把汁炒黏糊了
Stir fry till the sauce is sticky
# 你看 这黏度够了
See, this is the right thickness.
# 放虾
Add shrimp
# 漂亮
Beautiful
# 关火
Turn off the heat
# 装盘 一看就皮酥
Plating. The shell looks crispy!
# 肉香
The meat is so tender.
# 扬头
Raising head
# 翘尾
raising tails
# 有小花吗 有
Do we have flowers? Yes.
# 嘿 多漂亮
Hey! So pretty
# 带花带一盒你知道吗
If you bring flowers, you should bring a whole box.
# 带一盒也不给别人使
Even if he brought a whole box, he wouldn't share with other people (joking).
# 我出去了 我也不给他服务了
I am going out, I won't help him anymore.
# 酥皮虾 大爷
Honey-glazed crispy shrimp. Taste it, Da Ye
# 真酥
So crispy
# 师父尝尝
Master, have a try.
# 您听 您听声音
Listen, listen to this sound
# 酥脆
Crispy
# 市场上流行的大名菜
Super popular dish these days
# 今天刚强给呈现出来
Today, Gangqiang demonstrated it here
# 比外边还好看
Even better than those in the restaurants
# 摆了这么多花 花花草草的
Added these flowers to decorate
# 确实装的很美
Plating is pretty
# 今天这道菜
The dish he cooked today
# 确实在我们北京餐饮界
is sold everywhere
# 哪家都卖
every restaurant in Beijing
# 但是不同
But it is different
# 今天我吃的是最好的
This is the best I have had so far
# 为什么
Why?
# 在师父的传承之下 指导之下
Inherited from the master’s guidance
# 肉呢鲜嫩 外皮酥脆
The meat is tender and the shell is crispy
# 口味特别得当 适口
The taste is particularly pleasant and palatable
# 什么都离不开师父
I can't finish this without Master
# 在师父的精心的点缀之下
Under Master’s careful decoration
# 这菜非常完美
This dish is perfect
# 所以我一看
So I decided
# 给刚强点个赞
To give Gangqiang a thumbs-up
# 谢谢大爷
Thanks, Da Ye
# 谢谢师父
Thanks, Master
# 祝大家晚安
Good night everyone
# 晚安
Good night
# 祝大家幸福 晚安
I wish you all the best and good night
# 然后祝大爷
Then wish Da Ye
# 祝大爷越来越好
Wish Da Ye better and better
# 这段肯定不 裁了
The last part is definitely not (good). Remove it.